Register to The Thomas de Hartmann Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Items Relating to G.I. Gurdjieff, Series XI
  - Lecture by Gurdjieff., 7 p.; 27 cm. (Box 30, Folder 270)
    1923 Aug. 21.
    Given at Fontainebleau.
  - Lecture (possibly by Gurdjieff), 1 p.; 27 cm. (Box 30, Folder 270)
  - Meetings with remarkable men, my impressions of the film / Katherine Hulme. -- New York: Remar, 1979., 8 p.; 22 cm. (Box 30, Folder 270)
    With Aug. 10, 1979 advertisement of film from the New York Times.
  - Notes on hypnosis (possibly by Gurdjieff), 20 p.; 19 to 27 cm. (Box 30, Folder 270)
  - Struggle of the magicians / G. I. Gurdjieff. -- n.d., 36 p.; 28 cm. (Box 30, Folder 271)
    Ballet scenario.
  - Struggle of the magicians / G. I. Gurdjieff. -- n.d., 34 p.; 28 cm. (Box 30, Folder 271)
  - Struggle of the magicians / G. I. Gurdjieff. -- n.d., 33 p.; 26 cm. (Box 30, Folder 271)
  - Struggle of the magicians / G. I. Gurdjieff. -- n.d., 33 p.; 27 cm. (Box 30, Folder 271)
  - Unidentified., 6 p.; 35 cm. (Box 30, Folder 272)
    Typescript in Russian, carbon copy.
    Manuscript annotations.
- Items Relating to Wassily Kandinsky, Series XII
  (Not Der Gelbe Klang)
  - Books and Brochures, XII.A
    - Kandinsky in Munich: 1896-1914 / Thomas M. Messer, Carl E. Schorske, Peter Javelich, Peg Weiss. -- New York: Guggenheim Foundation, 1982., 312 p.; 26 cm. (Box 31, Folder 273)
      Catalog of the 1982 exhibition at Guggenheim.
      Includes selected bibliography and index of artists.
    - Kandinsky und München, Begegnungen und Wandlungen, 1896-1914 / Armin Zweite, Peter Javelich, Johannes Langner, Sixten Ringbom, Cart E. Schorske, Peg Weiss. -- München: Prestel, 1982., 450 p.; 24 cm. (Box 31, Folder 273)
      Includes selected bibliography and index.
      Catalog of the 1982 exhibition at Städtische Galerie im Lenbachhaus, München.
    - The Blaue Reiter Almanac / edited by Wassily Kandinsky and Franz Marc; new documentary edition edited by Klaus Lankheit. - New York: Viking, 1974., 296 p.; 21 cm. (Box 31, Folder 274)
      Includes index of names.
    - Kandinsky in Munich, 1896-1914., 8 p.; 28 cm. (Box 31, Folder 275)
      Brochure from 1982 exhibition at Guggenheim Museum.
    - Kandinsky und München., 3 p.; 21 cm. (Box 31, Folder 275)
      Brochure from 1982 München exhibition.
  - Clippings, XII.B
    - Clippings (Box 31, Folder 276)
      - [French and Russian], 1972; 4 items.
      - [Spanish and German], 1982; 29 items.
      - [English], 1982; 28 items.
  - Miscellaneous, XII.C
    - Miscellaneous (Box 31, Folder 277)
      - Poems by Kandinsky, manuscript., 5 items.
      - 2 p. from notebook, photocopy., 1 item.
      - Kandinsky exhibition announcement, 1934.; 1 item.
      - Manuscript note regarding Kandinsky., 1 item.
      - Guggenheim Museum calendar of events, 1982.; 1 item.